## **JOSEPH FITZSIMMONS**

WEB DEVELOPER



DENVER, CO



314.304.8268



joe@hoseb.com

#### SKILLS

- HTML / HTML5
- CSS / CSS3 / SASS / Compass
- JavaScript / jQuery
- Require JS
- JSHint
- Foundation
- AJAX / FLEX
- · XML / XSL
- JSON / SOAP
- Jira
- Git / Subversion
- Relational Database Concepts: PL/SQL, MySQL, MS SQL
- eCommerce: Demandware
- Adobe Suite: Photoshop, Flash, Dreamweaver
- CMS and Enterprise Apps: WordPress, Drupal, SharePoint
- Various IDEs: Eclipse, Visual Studio
- PHP
- SEO
- Analytics: Adobe Analytics, Google, Tealium Tag Management

#### **EDUCATION & AWARDS**

#### **Vatterott College**

St. Louis, MO, 2004-2006 Associates of Science: Information Systems

#### **Demandware**

DW Developer Certified in 2013

#### **IABC**

**Bronze Quill Award 2010** 

#### **Step Two Designs**

Intranet Innovation Award 2008

#### **PROFILE**

Creative web developer with nine years' experience creating and managing sites for major companies in both the financial and retail sectors. Excels in meeting simultaneous long and short-term deadlines and ushering projects from inception to delivery. Shared roles in multiple top-down redesigns, one of which exceeded an optimistic quarterly sales goal of 15 million dollars for NewBalance.com.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### M0. ST. LOUIS,

### **NEW BALANCE**

#### eCommerce Web Developer 06/2013 - present

- · Develops and documents technical solutions in response to enhancement and optimization requests regarding New Balance's eCommerce websites.
- · Participates and leads coding of solutions and assists with quality assurance activities including unit testing, system testing and solution validation.
- · Performs daily builds and promotion of code to the development environment for subsequent testing and offers leadership to entire development team.
- · Ensures best practices are established and followed and assists lessexperienced developers with technical challenges.

ST. LOUIS, MO.

#### SCOTTRADE

Intranet Developer 03/2009 - 05/2013

- · Was responsible for the implementation and coding of all CSS, jQuery, JavaScript and HTML for the Scottrade Intranet.
- · Was the point of contact for all projects and applications and reviewed all Work Requests from varying departments within Scottrade.
- · Worked with third party vendors to consume API's, track site analytics, improve SEO and site usability.
- · Marketed, promoted and branded website using style guides, banners and general promotions and streamlined processes with reusable pages, templates and styles.

## ST. LOUIS, MO.

#### **SCOTTRADE**

#### Intranet Administrator and Content Engineer 12/2006 - 03/2009

- · Was involved in applications from development to production and facilitated QA, UAT and Regression Testing for enhancements.
- Gathered functional requirements, created technical specifications and maintained competitive architecture with other businesses.
- · Administrated permissions and roles for secured content.
- · Answered support calls and delegated responsibilities to co-workers.

# ST. LOUIS, MO.

#### **SCOTTRADE**

#### Corporate Communications Intern 03/2006 - 12/2006

- · Assisted in conceptualization and execution of high-level technical plans.
- · Consulted with business groups to clarify requirements and feasibility.
- · Helped to provide technical solutions and participated in discussions to expand knowledge of systems and processes.
- Assisted with technical support and triaged issues as needed.